Guide to the Brooklyn High School newspaper collection BCMS.0030
Brooklyn Collection
Brooklyn High School Newspaper Collection
1853-2005
Brooklyn Collection
BCMS.0030
9.3 Linear Feet in 8 flat boxes
A collection of news publications from Brooklyn high schools, covering academic life as well as events in their communities.
The digitized portions of this collection are available on the Internet Archive.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This is an artifical collection created by Brooklyn Collection staff. Some of the papers were originally sent to Brooklyn Public Library for patron use. The specific source of the majority of the collection is unknown.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in folders alphabetically by school name. Within each folder, the papers are arranged chronologically. The date range for each paper does not necessarily indicate continuous coverage, but rather the earliest and latest dates available.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The digital surrogates for this collection should be used in place of the originals whenever possible. If the originals must be used, the researcher should note that the majority of the materials in this collection are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact cbhreference@bklynlibrary.org at least two weeks prior to research visit.
Related Materials
Brooklyn Yearbook collection (BCMS.0031)
Class Photograph collection (BCMS.0029)
Brooklyn ephemera collection (BCMS.0007), Brooklyn Historical Society ephemera collection (ARC.272) and Brooklyn Collection clippings files: each has folders dedicated to individual schools.
Brooklyn schools collection (CBHM.0006)
Scope and Contents
The Brooklyn High School newspaper collection consists of news publications from Brooklyn high schools. School news receives the most attention in the papers, but community events, as well as matters of national and international interest, are reported on as well. One example of this coverage is the writing done by students – in essays, interviews, poems, and reporting – on the assassination of John F. Kennedy. The bulk of the papers in the collection span the mid-1950s to the mid-1960s. Many famous Brooklynites appear in the pages of these publications, such as Bobby Fischer (Erasmus Hall High School), Janet Yellen (Fort Hamilton High School), and Bernie Sanders (James Madison High School).
Private schools -- New York (State) -- New York.; Public schools -- New York (State) -- New York.; Student newspapers and periodicals
- Abraham Lincoln High School
  - Lincoln Log, October 1958 - June 1964 (Box 6 - restricted)
    Scope and Contents
    21 issues
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Paper is in poor condition. Researchers should use the digital surrogates.
- Alexander Hamilton Vocational High School
  - The Spotlight, December 1961 - June 1963 (Box 1)
    8 issues
- All Saints High School
  - The Flame, December 1958 - Spring 1964 (Box 1)
    13 issues
- Bay Ridge High School
  - The Ridge Echo, January 1961 - March 1961 (Box 1)
    2 issues
- The Berkeley Institute
  - The Blotter, December 1962 - December 1963 (Box 1)
    6 issues
- Bishop Ford Central High School
  - High Point, Vols. 1-7, 1961-1994 (Box 7)
  - High Point, Vol. 2, No. 2, May 1964 (Box 1)
  - High Point, Vols. 8-18, 1983-1994 (Box 8)
- Bishop Loughlin Memorial High School
  - Jamesonian, October 1958 - February 1965 (Box 1)
    52 issues
- Bishop McDonnell Memorial High School
  - The Laurel, October 1962 - December 1964 (Box 1)
    18 issues
- Boys High School
  - Boys High Weekly, December 1940, September 1941 (Box 6 - restricted)
    Two issues. The December 16, 1940 issue is partial and seems to be a test run as it has editing marks. The September 24, 1941 issue is the final issue of this publication.
    These issues have not been digitized. They are in poor condition and should only be handled if absolutely necessary.
  - The Red and Black, October 1941 - June 1964 (Box 6 - restricted)
    16 issues
    Not all issues have been digitized. The paper is in poor condition and researchers should use the digital surrogates when possible.
- Brooklyn Female Academy
  - School-Room Echoes, January 1853 (Box 1)
    Note
    1 issue
- Brooklyn High School of Automotive Trades
  - The Spark Plug, December 1961 - June 1963 (Box 1)
    10 issues
- Brooklyn Preparatory School
  - Blue Jug, December 1958 - November 1964 (Box 1)
    26 issues
- Brooklyn Technical High School
  - Survey, September 1958 - April 1964 (Box 6 - restricted)
    44 issues
- Bushwick High School
  - Bushwick Bulletin, November 1961 - May 1975 (Box 1)
    33 issues
- Catherine McAuley High School
  - The McAuleyan, November 1958 - April 1963 (Box 1)
    14 issues
- Clara Barton Vocational High School
  - Barton Clarion, May 1958 - June 1962 (Box 2)
- East New York Vocational and Technical High School
  - East New Yorker, October 1958 - June 1964 (Box 2)
    23 issues
- Eli Whitney Vocational High School
  - Eli Whitney Green and Gold, November 1961 - January 1965 (Box 2)
- Erasmus Hall High School
  - The Erasmian, November 1899 - June 1907 (Box 2)
    4 issues
  - The Dutchman, May 1950 - November 1961 (Box 6 - restricted)
    28 issues
  - The Dutchman, December 1961 - February 1965 (Box 2)
    46 issues
- Euphrasian High School
  - Euphradio, February 1959 - Summer 1962 (Box 2)
    9 issues
- Fontbonne Hall
  - The Folio, March 1961 - June 1963 (Box 2)
- Fort Hamilton High School
  - The Pilot, November 1957 - January 1965 (Box 4 - restricted)
    64 issues
- Franklin K. Lane High School
  - Lane Reporter, October 1958 - 1975 (Box 4 - restricted)
    17 issues
- George W. Wingate High School
  - Wingate World, April 1961 - June 1965 (Box 4 - restricted)
    24 issues
- Girls' High School
  - Girls' High Record, April 1937 - June 1964 (Box 4 - restricted)
    66 issues
- James Madison High School
  - Madison Highway, October 1958 - May 1961 (Box 6 - restricted)
    General
    22 issues
- John Jay High School
  - The Double Jay, October 1961 - November 1964 (Box 5 - restricted)
    11 issues
- Lafayette High School
  - Lafayette News, November 1961 - December 1964 (Box 5 - restricted)
    15 issues
- The Mercy Juniorate
  - The Misericordia, June 1962 (Box 2)
- Midwood High School
  - Midwood Argus, October 1958 - March 1969 (Box 5 - restricted)
    Some issues are in poor condition. Researchers should use the digital surrogates.
- New Utrecht High School
  - The NUHS, October 1961 - January 1965 (Box 5 - restricted)
    19 issues
- Polytechnic Preparatory Country Day School
  - The Polygraphic, April 1935 (Box 2)
- Prospect Heights High School
  - The Scribe, November 1961 - April 1962 (Box 6 - restricted)
- Queen of All Saints
  - The Gleaner, November 1958 - December 1960 (Box 2)
    3 issues
- Saint Agnes Seminary
  - The Gazing Ball, October 1958 - December 1961 (Box 2)
- Saint Angela Hall
  - The Angelus, June 1959 - November 1964 (Box 2)
- Saint Ann's School
  - The Saint Ann's Ram, September 2001 - December 2005 (Box 2)
  - The Saint Ann's Corner Paper, June 2004 - June 2005 (Box 2)
- Saint Augustine's High School
  - The Lance, November 1958 (Box 3)
- Saint Brendan Diocesan High School
  - Stella Matutina, October 1961 - December 1964 (Box 3)
- Saint Edmund's High School
  - Quarterly Gleanings, Winter 1958-1959 (Box 3)
  - Edmund News, Fall 1961 (Box 3)
- Saint Francis Prep
  - The Seraph, November 1958 - June 1962 (Box 3)
- Saint Francis Xavier
  - The Courier, October 1958 - May 1959 (Box 3)
- Saint John's Preparatory School
  - Red Owl, October 1958 - June 1959 (Box 3)
    7 issues
- Saint Joseph's Commercial High School
  - Parmentier, October 1958 - December 1963 (Box 3)
- Saint Michael's Commercial High School
  - The Victor, November 1958 - April 1960 (Box 3)
- Saint Stephen's High School
  - Stephenite, October 1961 - March 1962 (Box 3)
  - St. Stephen's Gazette, October 1962 - February 1965 (Box 3)
- Saint Saviour High School
  - Skyline, October 1958 - November 1961 (Box 3)
- Samuel J. Tilden High School
  - Tilden Topics, November 1958 - January 1965 (Box 5 - restricted)
    43 issues
- Sarah J. Hale Vocational High School
  - Green and Gold, February 1960 - December 1963 (Box 3)
- Sheepshead Bay High School
  - Bay Times, December 1961 (Box 5 - restricted)
- Thomas Jefferson High School
  - Liberty Bell, November 1961 - January 1965 (Box 5 - restricted)
  - Liberty Bell, June 1938 (Box 6 - restricted)
- William E. Grady Vocational and Technical High School
  - Grady Headliner, December 1961 (Box 3)
- William H. Maxwell Vocational High School
  - Maxwell Magpie, September 1958 (Box 3)
- Xaverian High School
  - X-Press, March 1962 - Fall 1964 (Box 3)